Ching-Yu Tseng

Al Researcher M.Sc. in NTU

National Taiwan University

Taipei City, Taiwan

Email: cytseng@cmlab.csie.ntu.edu.tw

Website: https://sty61010.github.io/

GitHub Linkedin Google Scholar

Research Interest

3D/2D Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Autonomous Driving

Ching-Yu is a graduate research assistant at Communication & Multimedia Lab, National Taiwan University (NTU), supervised by Prof. Winston H. Hsu. His research focuses on Machine Learning and 3D Computer Vision. He has won the top 3rd in the top conference NIPS2021. Recently, he has been working on camera-based perception for autonomous driving.

Publication

CrossDTR: Cross-view and Depth-guided Transformers for 3D Object Detection / Under Submission [paper] [code] [project page][video]

Ching-Yu Tseng, Yi-Rong Chen, Hsin-Ying Lee, Tsung-Han Wu, Wen-Chin Chen, Winston H. Hsu

3rd Place Solution for NeurIPS 2021 Shifts Challenge: Vehicle Motion Prediction / NIPS2021 Competition [paper][competition][video]

Ching-Yu Tseng, Po-Shao Lin, Yu-Jia Liou, Kuan-Chih Huang, Winston H. Hsu

Learning from 2D: Contrastive Pixel-to-Point Knowledge Transfer for 3D Pretraining / Arxiv [paper]

Yueh-Cheng Liu, Yu-Kai Huang, Hung-Yueh Chiang, Hung-Ting Su, Zhe-Yu Liu, Chin-Tang Chen, Ching-Yu Tseng, Winston H. Hsu

Education

National Taiwan University / Master of Science (Sep. 2021 - Present)

Major in Computer Science and Information Engineering

Advisor: Winston H. Hsu

• Research Topic: Camera-based Perception of Autonomous Driving

•Overall GPA: 4.08/4.3

National Tsing Hua University / Bachelor of Science (Sep. 2017- Jun. 2021)

Major in Computer Science

Advisor: Shan-Hung Wu

• Research Topic: Defense of Adversarial Attack on Image Classification

•College Student Research Scholarship, MOST.

•Rank: top 11%; Overall GPA: 4.02/4.3; Academic Award: 2017, 2021.

Work Experience

National Taiwan University / UNIX System Administrator (Feb. 2022 - Oct. 2022)

Advisor: Winston H. Hsu

• Unix Manager of Communication & Multimedia Lab, National Taiwan University.

Shanghai Jiao Tong University / Visiting Researcher (July 2018 - Sep. 2018)

Advisor: Hong-Tao Lu

• Face Detection and Recognition Embedding System:

• Develop an embedding system for face recognition for lab members at SJTU.

Teaching Experience

National Tsing Hua University / Teaching Assistant (Feb. 2020- Jun. 2020)

Course: CS241001 Software Design and Studio

Advisor: Shan-Hung Wu

• Teach students to build personal websites with React framework.

• Teach students to utilize databases such as MongoDB and MySQL.

Honors & Awards

- Third Place, NIPS2021 Competition (2021)
 - NeurIPS 2021 Shifts Challenge: Vehicle Motion Prediction
- College Student Research Scholarship, Ministry of Science and Technology (2020)
 - Research scholarship from Ministry of Science and Technology.
- First Place, Kaggle Competition in CS5656 Deep Learning (2020)
 - Deep Learning Competition in Department of Computer Science, **National Tsing Hua University**
- Summer Oversea Experience Scholarship (2018)
 - Exchange program to **Shanghai Jiao Tong University** for visiting researcher.
- Academic Award 2 times in **National Tsing Hua University** (2017, 2021)
 - top 5% of students in the class with the highest GPA.

Skills

Programming: C/C++, Python, Unity, Matlab, Javascript, HTML, CSS.

Languages: English(fluent, TOEFL 91/120, TOEIC 815/990), Chinese(native).

Libraries/Tools: PyTorch, OpenCV, Open3D, MMD etection3D, Scikit-learn, LaTex.